In this last exercise,
最后一个练习里
you're going to write code for a full ETL pipeline.
你要编写整个 ETL 管道的代码
I wanted to walk you through the Jupyter notebook,
我先带你浏览一下这个 Jupyter notebook
so that you have a better sense of what
让你更清楚
all the code is doing and what you need to fill out.
各部分代码的作用 以及你需要填写的内容
Here, this first cell connects to a SQLite database called worldbank.db,
第一个单元格连接到一个叫worldbank.db 的 SQLite 数据库
and creates a table that is going to hold gdp data.
创建一个用来保存 GDP 数据的表格
You do not need to do anything in this code other than execute the cell.
你只需要运行这个单元格即可
In the lower portion of the ETL pipeline,
在 ETL 管道的后段
this is the table where you're going to end up loading your data.
你要把数据加载到这个表格里
The second cell, has a function called extract line.
第二个单元格 有一个函数 extract_line
You don't need to do anything in this code cell either,
同样 你只需要
besides executing the cell.
运行这个单元格
This function is a Python generator.
这个函数是一个 Python 的生成器
You don't necessarily need to understand how
是否理解这个生成器如何工作
this generator works in order to complete the exercise,
不会影响你通过这个项目
but it'll be helpful if you open
但如果你打开注释中的链接阅读一些代码
the link that's in the comments and read a little bit about them.
可能对你有帮助
Essentially, a generator is like a normal function except,
本质上 生成器和普通的函数一样
instead of a return statement,
只是 return 语句不同
a generator has a yield statement.
生成器使用的是 yield 语句
Generators allow you to use functions in a for-loop.
你可以在 for 循环里使用生成器
In essence, this function will allow you to read in a data file one line at a time,
所以 生成器可以实现每次读进数据文件的一行
run a transformation on that one row data,
对该行数据进行转换
load the data, and then move on to the next row in the file to repeat the process.
加载数据 然后继续处理下一行数据 不断循环
The third cell, is where you're going to start writing code.
第三个单元格 你要开始写代码了
This cell contains a function called transform indicator data.
这个单元格包含一个叫做 transform_indicator_data 的函数
This function receives a line from
这个函数从一个 csv 文件接收一行数据
a csv file and transforms the data in preparation for a load step.
然后进行转换 为加载步骤做准备
Keep in mind what a row of data looks like in this csv file.
记得这个 csv 文件中数据的结构
It has a country name,
有 国家名
and an indicator variable,
指标变量
and then a column for each year.
还有一列是年份
This is the same gdp data you've been working with earlier in the exercises.
这和你之前在练习中使用的 GDP 数据是一样的
Your task will be to transform this data into a list of lists,
你的任务是叫这些数据转换成 列表的列表 (a list of lists)
where each entry has the country,
每个子列表包含 国家
country abbreviation, year, and the value.
国家简称 年份 和 数值
The fourth cell, contains a function called load indicator data,
第四个单元格 有一个函数 叫做 load_indicator_data,
and you'll have to fill out code in this function as well.
你需要补全这个函数的代码
This function loads the transform data into the gdp table in the worldbank.db database.
这个函数将转换好的数据加载到 worldbank.db 数据库的GDP 表格中
In this part of the code,
在这部分代码中
you're going to prepare a SQL query that will load each entry into the database.
你要使用 SQL 语句 将每个数据项加入到数据库中
The fifth cell runs the ETL pipeline.
第五个单元格是运行整个 ETL 管道
You don't actually need to do anything here other than run the code but,
你只需要运行这段代码就可以了
please read through the code to understand what it's doing.
但为了理解你在做什么 先通读这段代码
This code is using
这段代码用到了
the extract lines generator that was loaded earlier in the Jupyter notebook.
事先加载到Jupyter notebook 中的 extract_lines
The sixth cell, runs a query against
第六个单元格 对数据库运行了一条查询语句
the database to make sure everything worked correctly.
保证数据库正常运行
All you need to do here is run the code and make sure that the output makes sense.
你只需要运行这段代码 保证输出正常即可
Just as a reminder,
提醒一下
you only need to modify the third and fourth cells in this Jupyter notebook.
你只需要修改 Jupyter notebook 里的第三和第四个单元格
The other cells you just need to execute.
其他的单元格你只需要运行一下